Hello, in today's episode of Bug Bounty Reports Explained,
you will learn how two guys from high school hacked GitHub private pages
for $35,000 by chaining four different vulnerabilities.
Their names are Robert Chen and Phillip who uses nickname, @ginkoid.
Link to the original blog posts and their profiles are in the description.
Enjoy.
But before we jump into the technical stuff,
I'd like to encourage you to sign up for BBRE newsletter.
You will get it on your email every second week,
and you will not only find there the most interesting stories
from Bug Bounty and security world in general,
but also some tips about productivity
or chill out with some more personal stuff from me.
Here's the agenda of the first issue that was sent a week ago.
Generally, those newsletters are not available anywhere,
but for the first one, I made an exception.
You can get it by visiting the link that's in the description
and on the video right now.
Sign up before 9th May to get the second issue.
Let's now start the explanation.
GitHub pages is a service that allows you
to create a website straight from the GitHub repository.
And it's also possible to create a private page
that's only available with authentication,
but the GitHub pages does not have its own login panel.
It's also on different domain.
So cookies from GitHub.com are not sent there.
So developers created this flow of authentication,
which uses cookies from GitHub.com.
First, GitHub.io sets a random nonce inside GitHub pages session cookie.
Then it redirects the user to GitHub.com with this nonce as the parameter,
but also with a page ID and the path,
then GitHub.com checks if the user is logged in,
generates a token and redirects the user back to GitHub.io.
Those three parameters are passed throughout the whole flow.
Then, GitHub.io checks if the nonce from the parameter
is equal to the nonce from the cookie.
If it is, the token gets inside the cookie
and the page ID is also being put inside the cookie.
And with those cookies,
the user can visit GitHub page that he wanted to view.
In step five, the value from the parameter page ID
is being put into the GitHub page’s ID cookie.
Page ID is an integer number.
It identifies the page to which user
will be redirected after the authentication flow
and the page lookup converts the cookie to integer number.
So if your page ID is 123 with space at the end,
the space will be dropped by integer conversion.
But importantly, the cookie that will be sent back to you
is the one before the int conversion.
So with the space at the end.
You could inject %0D %0A there as it was ignored by integer conversion.
Those are the CRLF characters that mean a new line.
Then you got a strange looking response back to your browser.
Usually, CLRF vulnerability is exploited by adding new headers
or changing the response body to an XSS payload.
But here you could only inject white space characters
and in non white space character causes an integer conversion
to throw an exception so there was no real impact to this.
The researchers had access to the source code
and they noticed that this page is served by nginx
and nginx is written in C where null byte terminates the C-string.
So it's always worth to give it a try.
Turned out it worked,
you could inject any characters after the null byte and they were ignored,
but null byte is not allowed in the header section of the response.
So you could only inject something in the body.
In fact, this was a 302 redirect,
where generally the response body is not processed by the browser.
But here, luckily the location header was after our injection point,
so it was not treated as header.
And in 302 responses, without the location header,
the body is processed normally.
With that, we can inject the HTML code in the response
and execute arbitrary JavaScript code, reaching our XSS.
But the problem is that this injection is in fifth request of the whole flow.
And you can't just take this one, put whatever in other parameters
and it will work. No, it wouldn't.
You need to send the victim into a valid authentication flow
just with this one malicious parameter.
And as you remember, we had three parameters there - nonce, path, and page ID.
Page ID will be our payload, path doesn't matter much.
The problem is the nonce.
Because GitHub.io checks if the nonce from the parameter
that comes from GitHub.com is the same as nonce in the cookie.
So you either need to predict the nonce or to set the cookie
to your known value and then send the same value as the parameter.
The potential attack scenario is that we have right access
to attacker.private-org.github.io
and we want to read another page from the same organization.
Let's say it's called flag.
Such scenario with user interaction
and being in the same organization would be granted $5,000 of bonus.
Our bug hunters decided to try the scenario where you set the cookie first,
considering we can’t control other sub domain of private-org.github.io.
This should be a bit easier.
The problem was that the cookie within nonce used the __Host- prefix.
It means that from attacker subdomain, you can only set the cookie
to attacker subdomain and not to the parent domain.
If there wasn't this prefix from attacker.private-org.github.io,
you could just set the cookie to the parent subdomain
and then it would also be sent to flag.private-org.github.io,
meaning that, you know the nonce from the subdomain,
and you can execute the cross-site scripting.
So you need to trick the server into thinking that the cookie has the __Host- prefix
while the browser thinks it doesn't.
Turns out that the __Host- prefix is case sensitive.
This means if you try to set the __Host- cookie to parent domain, it won't work.
But if you try the same with __HOST- using capital letters, it will work
because the browser doesn't consider this to be a valid host prefix,
but turns out that the server used by GitHub doesn't care about it at all.
While parsing cookies, it will strip the host part whatever the capitalization.
So you can set the host cookie using capital letters.
The browser will set it to the parent domain
because it's not a valid prefix while the server will also be happy
because it thinks that the cookie has the host prefix.
So this is the proof of concept that will be hosted
on attacker.private-org.github.io.
It will send the cookie to parent domain with nonce known by us.
And will send the victim into a valid authentication flow with nonce known by us.
And with page ID of the page that we want to attack.
Once the victim goes through the flow,
it gets back to GitHub page where the XSS is executed.
This way, you could access any page
that the attack victim would have access to.
This made hunters eligible for $5,000 bonus,
but they were hungry for more.
They wanted to escalate it to a no interaction bug.
And this escalation was made rather easy by cache poisoning vulnerability.
It was present on the same vulnerable endpoint
and the page was cached based on the integer value of page ID.
So if you would request the page with ID "123", or "123 ",
you would get the same cached response.
So if you would request it with our payload used previously,
then everyone that will visit the same page would get XSSed by you.
This means you'd no longer need user's interaction.
And you attack all pages of victims that visit this malicious page.
So this attack scenario no longer needed user interaction
and only required a read access to a page.
Such scenario would be granted $10,000 of bonus.
Now to get the maximum $15,000 bonus,
they needed to escalate it to an attacker that is outside the organization.
So if a GitHub page is completely public,
then this whole authentication flow doesn't happen.
But in case that there is a private repository that is then changed to public,
then each user that visits the page, still goes through the authentication flow,
but every GitHub user has read access to this private page.
And as you already saw read access to a page
is everything that you need to poison the cache with the XSS payload.
This means that the attack can be executed
by the attacker outside the organization.
All you need is a repository that was private
and had a GitHub private page, but was then changed to public.
And with that attack, our hunters were rewarded $15,000 of maximum bonus
plus $20,000 of base payment for a total of $35,000.
That's very good money, especially when you are 14 or 17 years old.
And that's it.
It's amazing how far little bugs were changed together
for a vulnerability with such a huge impact.
If you learn something new during this video, leave a like, or leave a subscription.
leave a like, or leave a subscription.
Also, sign up for my mailing list
to get the new issue of BBRE newsletter that will be out next Monday.
For now, thank you for watching and goodbye.